Oga, you wrote on your Twitter,
a lengthy thread about what the sanctions
can and cannot do to the Russian
government.
And specifically to put in.
And you said that western sanctions
will not topple the Russian regime.
Why not?
In order to understand what the effect
of sanctions is on toppling regime?
You have to understand how the
sanctions impact the ability of the
regime or the leader to distribute
the rents to his or her supporters.
Now, Russia is not a democracy,
has not been a democracy since
I'm gonna say 2003 or so.
When we're talking about the supporters of
the leader,
the people who supporters critical
for the leader to stay in power,
we are talking about the Top el, it es.
So in Russia, these Top el,
it es can be roughly grouped in 2 groups.
It's the oligarchs that we hear a lot about.
Those are the ones whose yards
are being arrested right now,
and who's the four foreign
accounts are being frozen.
The second group are the strong men.
So these are the closest
friends of president Britain,
who they usually go back
to Saint Petersburg times.
And these are people in government
positions who have influence on politics.
The oligarchs not have interest,
influence on politics.
So to understand why neither of the 2 groups
has any interest to bring down the regime,
you have to understand that the
oligarchs are affected by the sanctions
are probably not supporters of this war.
The oligars are politically powerless,
the way putting set up his regimes,
the ogark essentially got a lot of cash in
order to completely stay out of politics.
So the oligarchs, if they speak up,
all we have,
is to lose what they already have,
what they haven't lost
due to western sanctions.
But it's the capacitors that they can lose.
Forgive me for interrupting.
But I just want to jump in because
we've heard so much talk that the
oligarchs won't like that.
Their money and their yachts and
their homes are being taken away
that their accounts are being frozen.
And they're going to be the reason why
puton stops the war against Ukraine.
What's your take on that analysis?
I I don't think so.
I agree.
Obviously,
they're not happy about their
foreign properties being frozen.
They are not happy about losing access to
their foreign business partners and so on.
But you have to understand that the
majority of the wealth of these
people is still inside the country.
And if they speak up against the regime,
now they stand to potentially
lose their position,
lose their remaining wealth.
It's still a lot of money,
even though therefore,
and assets aren't small.
So then talk to me about these strong men,
the secondary group that you're talking
about are these military and KGB allies of
prudent that are in strategic positions.
Now.
Exactly.
These are the ST.
Petersburg group that he brought
and put into strategic positions.
These people do have political
power and do have a lot of
accents access to the president.
But the problem with these people is
that they on the whole are extremely
ideologically conservative.
I imagine are happy about the sanctions.
They would want Russia to
be isolated from the world.
They talk about it as fortress Russia.
They are welcoming anarchy.
They want Russia to be self sufficient.
They also are welcoming the hardening of the
regime that we see in
response to sanctions.
They are happy about the regime,
becoming a full dictatorship,
extremely repressive.
That's exactly what they want.
So they have no reason to topple the regime.
So it sounds like the two most powerful
political and economic sets of people.
In Russia.
Sanctions are not,
it's in their interest to keep
put on in his position.
Am I understanding that correctly?
Exactly.
So.