Rural North Carolina.
Researchers from Duke University
were working there on a long term
study of mental health problems in
a sample of nearly 1,500 children,
about 1/4 of whom from
the Cherokee reservation.
In 1996, during the study,
the Cherokee Indians in
North ca ro Li Na's great,
smoky mountains opened a casino.
But this was a casino with a difference.
It was different because some of the profits
from this casino were distributed equally
amongst families on the reservation.
And this lifted many of them out of poverty.
And this was an absolutely fantastic
opportunity for the researchers,
because this new money was
independent of anything the families
had done for themselves.
So it was literally a brand new factor.
This gave the researchers Jane Costello and
her colleagues a unique chance to test if
ending family poverty had any effect on
the mental health of the children.
The finding surprised even
the researchers themselves.
In just 4 years after the study began,
children whose families had moved out
of poverty showed a 40% reduction in
conduct and opposition disorders.
But there was no significant change
in conduct of Cherokee children
who had not been living in poverty.
This LED researches to conclude
that poverty was a factor in some
child mental health problems.